<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Arkansas GIS Office, State of Arkansas</origin>
        <title>County Boundaries of Arkansas</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <othercit>SPECIAL NOTE: Users should be aware the historical population figures were based upon the county boundary of the decade represented. Legislative Acts have changed the county boundary from decade to decade.</othercit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The county boundary is a publication of polygons of all counties in Arkansas. It represents the contemporary boundary of each county as established or altered by various Acts of the Arkansas Legislature. The database provides location, and population information for use in local and regional cartographic and spatial analysis applications.When necessary the data were adjusted to conform to known physical features recited in the Acts. This dataset does not represent exact legal boundaries as per surveyed description, but, rather a set of boundaries used for the administrative purposes that conforms to logical &amp; administrative rules. These polygons may be edited for the purpose of small spatial alignment changes based on new, enhanced or improved supporting base map data, such as orthoimagery, public land survey system (PLSS), or precision PLSS corner control data that improves the spatial accuracy of the existing geometry.</abstract>
      <purpose>The data contained within this collection represents the County Boundaries of Arkansas.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-94.618315</westbc>
        <eastbc>-89.616087</eastbc>
        <northbc>36.531986</northbc>
        <southbc>32.969240</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>county</themekey>
        <themekey>historic</themekey>
        <themekey>boundary</themekey>
        <themekey>population</themekey>
        <themekey>counties</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>PUBLIC DOMAIN - Pre-release publication for evaluation and business process testing. Anticipated for PRODUCTION in January, 2021.</useconst>
    <datacred>Arkansas GIS Office</datacred>
    <native> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.6.0.8321</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>75</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>NAD 1983 UTM Zone 15N</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-93.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0001</absres>
            <ordres>0.0001</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>asdi.BOUNDARIES.COUNTY_BOUNDARY</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the legal name of the county.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATEFIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the five-digit unique numerical code for the state and county based on the Federal Information Processing Standard 173.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Federal Information Processing Standard 173</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTYFIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the three-digit unique numerical code for the county based on the Federal Information Processing Standard 173.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Federal Information Processing Standard 173.</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1900</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1900 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1910</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1910 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1920</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1920 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1930</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1930 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1940</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1940 decennial census. </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1950</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1950 decennial census. </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1960</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1960 decennial census. </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1970</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1970 decennial census.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1980</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1980 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP1990</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 1990 decennial census. </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP2000</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 2000 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP2010</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 2010 decennial census.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP2020</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the US Census Bureau population count from the 2020 decennial census.  </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EFF_DATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the effective date of the latest boundary change of the county.  For this publication, this is the effective date the Act of the Arkansas Legislature. The Effective Date Format is YYYYMMDD.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>REV_DATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the revision date the individual boundary polygon was changed.  This is the edit date of the polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>REV_TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the type of edit revision to the boundary polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Legal Update </edomv>
            <edomvd>Represents a boundary revision resulting from a statutory procedure permitted by Arkansas law.  Tells the user the edit revision was a result of an Act of the Arkansas Legislature.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Arkansas GIS Office</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>Geometry Correction </edomv>
            <edomvd>Represents small spatial alignment changes based on new, enhanced or improved supporting basemap data, such as orthoimagery, public land survey, or precision PLSS corner control data that improves the spatial accuracy of the existing geometry.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Arkansas GIS Office</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SQ_MILES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stores the calculated square miles of area fully contained within the county.  Square mileage area calculation derived from geometry calculation of each boundary polygon.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Arkansas GIS Office</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape.STArea()</attrlabl>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape.STLength()</attrlabl>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20201008</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metuc>PUBLIC DOMAIN</metuc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>